<?xml-stylesheet href="/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bao Tran Hoang</title>
    <link>https://btrhoang.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bao Tran Hoang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 17:39:19 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://btrhoang.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Me on TV</title>
        <link>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/me_on_tv/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 17:39:19 +0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/me_on_tv/</guid>
        <description>Bao Tran Hoang https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/me_on_tv/ -&lt;p&gt;As the valedictorian of HCMC high school entrance exam,  I have got the chance to be interviewed twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=100% controls autoplay&gt;
    &lt;source src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/videos/HTV_1.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
    Your browser does not support the video tag.  
&lt;/video&gt;


&lt;video width=100% controls autoplay&gt;
    &lt;source src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/videos/HTV_2.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
    Your browser does not support the video tag.  
&lt;/video&gt;

- https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/me_on_tv/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Sugar</title>
        <link>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/sugar/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 17:36:41 +0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/sugar/</guid>
        <description>Bao Tran Hoang https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/sugar/ -&lt;p&gt;Growing up in a single-parent household, I have somewhat a special emotional attachment to orphaned children. At SUGAR, I have got the chance to interact with and add values to the lives of children at shelters. Leading a network of hundreds of volunteers and enlisting support from our 33,000 followers on Facebook, I’m contented that I can help take care of them both mentally and financially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular trips to orphanages have brought home to me many heartful values. Although seemingly lacking in what others deemed as a “real” father or mother figure, all the kids showed love and care for me in the most charming way possible. Every time I arrive, they welcome with a liveshow of our fav songs. And when it’s time for me to go back home, they help me wear my jackets, and remind me of my belongings since I’m awfully absent-minded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My members and I genuinely consider them our brothers and sisters, and I’m sure they also do.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/sugar/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Science at an aesthetic glance</title>
        <link>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/sci-glance/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 20:38:21 +0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/sci-glance/</guid>
        <description>Bao Tran Hoang https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/sci-glance/ -&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/sci-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/sci-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/sci-3.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/sci-4.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/sci-5.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/sci-6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/sci-7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/sci-8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/sci-9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/sci-10.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/sci-11.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/sci-glance/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>My four-year journey at a glance</title>
        <link>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/four-year/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 20:17:48 +0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/four-year/</guid>
        <description>Bao Tran Hoang https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/four-year/ -&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/yas22-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/yas22-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/yas22-3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/yas22-4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/yas22-5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/nko-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/nko-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://btrhoang.github.io/images/nko-3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/four-year/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>A revitalizing piece</title>
        <link>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/revitalizing/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 20:11:32 +0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/revitalizing/</guid>
        <description>Bao Tran Hoang https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/revitalizing/ -&lt;p&gt;Whenever my triumphant steps pass a reflective surface, my course changes as every possible angle is now brutally reflected. I used to dread my plump silhouette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a young age, I was accustomed to being called chubby. My relatives would never stop reprimanding me for being overweight, and my classmates who were jealous of my academic achievements told me my size would prevent me from ever being successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These remarks only served to make me study harder to shift their attention from my appearance to my accomplishments. Whenever I saw my reflection, I would go into self-denial: I was not at all chubby!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, deep down, I knew the truth. In fact, I turned down an invitation from a boy whom I adored since I didn’t feel worthy because of my physical appearance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my turning point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I secretly embarked on a weight loss journey by following a Korean idol’s diet on the Internet that promised to help me lose ten kilograms every week. The daily meal plan consisted of two eggs, two slices of bread, and a banana. I almost fainted twice. That was when I seriously began to watch health-focused videos featuring nutritionists to build a scientifically-proven and long-term weight loss plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first few months, I tried every imaginable 30-minute cardio exercise on YouTube. Initially, it felt like my heart would give out. I recall trying to trick my brain: &amp;ldquo;Only 40 seconds left, just like brushing my teeth!&amp;rdquo; I consumed exactly 1,200 calories every day and bought a kitchen scale to track my intake. I opted for more wholesome, low-calorie food, such as sweet potatoes, fish, shrimp, and tropical fruits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the first month, I lost two kilograms. Although I was still chubby, I started to truly appreciate my body. My newfound self-esteem led me to enroll in my school’s solo singing contest, wear fashionable, form-fitting clothes to MUN conferences, and confidently strike up a conversation with that boy who had expressed interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My efforts inspired  family and friends. I then suggested that they begin by simply lowering their sugar intake and walking a minimum of 5,000 steps a day. Witnessing their progress, I was so motivated to help others that my Facebook science-themed page, Scientiador, featured a series on nutrition. After recruiting a team of like-minded thirty high school students, I offered tips about counting calories, reading food labels, and the harmful consequences of consuming too much sugar. We then collaborated with local fitness influencers to conduct workshops to teach participants how to make healthy smoothies. I now have a community of 4,000 followers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have managed to shed 15 kilograms by making wise food choices. I now know that striving for a healthy lifestyle is an endeavor of a lifetime. In fact, my insight has influenced my career decision and given me my life’s mission. I recently added one more goal to my vision board: after earning my credentials, I will launch a foundation to help overweight Vietnamese teenagers overcome their body insecurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P/S: These pictures marked the time when I was the most chubby.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/revitalizing/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>A Proud Mom</title>
        <link>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/a-proud-mom/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 14:02:34 +0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/a-proud-mom/</guid>
        <description>Bao Tran Hoang https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/a-proud-mom/ -&lt;p&gt;I arrived home at 10 p.m. on the final day of the three-day conference. I didn’t cry, neither in the closing ceremony nor the dinner party, despite seeing many of my members failing to choke back their tears. Instead, I calmly slept for twelve hours to replenish my energy, getting myself ready for the upcoming post-event tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Deputy Secretary General, I long attached myself to the responsibility of remaining mentally strong on all occasions so that my members can always have a firm shoulder to lean on. Many a time I saw Bennard and I in our depths of despair when faced with apparently insoluble challenges. Still, we had to keep most things to ourselves while motivating everyone to keep going with their assigned tasks. We prioritized others&amp;rsquo; mental health and emotions, so sometimes neglected our own. We still kept that habit, even though Bennard had struck the gavel, signaling the end of NKO MUN’ 23.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, writing this appreciation post, I allowed myself to return to my more girly version, the more sentimental one. I remembered many, many delegates congratulated me on such a well thought out event, and others saying “Impressive organization!” when I gave them our “Thank you letter” while signing placards. I also vividly recalled the way everyone sang along with our performers and the homely atmosphere that we managed to create in the whole conference, especially in the closing ceremony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt like a proud mom, although not a perfect one. I usually got mad at my members when things went wrong, and apologized to them 30 minutes later. I was sometimes not far-sighted or detail-oriented enough to make our event flawless or exceptional. But like other moms, I’m sure I have done everything imaginable to make this event possible, and to ensure that every single delegate, chair, and organizer felt at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the first organization I have worked at as a leader, but the only one that has presented me with unprecedented obstacles that challenged me to my limits. Bennard and I have grown a whole lot after those hardships, and we hope to have created a space for all of you to develop and explore yourselves. And it&amp;rsquo;s touching for me to see us becoming increasingly close together after those difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love every single one of you guys. I remember every detail of the memories each of you shares with me. I can&amp;rsquo;t be so sure whether we will have a chance to reunite, but it&amp;rsquo;s a pleasure for me to have met, talked to, and hugged you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you all for being an indispensable part of Nang Khieu Open Model United Nations - NKO MUN, and an indispensable part of me.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/a-proud-mom/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>About</title>
        <link>https://btrhoang.github.io/about/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 19:55:31 +0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://btrhoang.github.io/about/</guid>
        <description>Bao Tran Hoang https://btrhoang.github.io/about/ -&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite subject:&lt;/strong&gt; Chemistry, Biology, Computer Science (normally a slow coder but can become laser-focused in exams)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite songs:&lt;/strong&gt; old, melodic Vietnamese songs. Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OyK6H09nqJU&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OyK6H09nqJU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most proud achievement:&lt;/strong&gt; lost around 20kgs healthily during COVID without personal trainers and lack of a variety of food choices. Shared my experience with a dozen of peers, and they also succeeded!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I do to unwind:&lt;/strong&gt; Put my earphones on, then sing and dance (a perfect stress-reliever!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biggest fear:&lt;/strong&gt; Ophidiophobia&lt;/p&gt;
- https://btrhoang.github.io/about/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 