<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Bao Tran Hoang</title>
    <link>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Bao Tran Hoang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 20:10:02 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Me on TV</title>
      <link>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/me_on_tv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 17:39:19 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/me_on_tv/</guid>
      <description>As the valedictorian of HCMC high school entrance exam, I have got the chance to be interviewed twice.
Your browser does not support the video tag. Your browser does not support the video tag. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sugar</title>
      <link>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/sugar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 17:36:41 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/sugar/</guid>
      <description>Growing up in a single-parent household, I have somewhat a special emotional attachment to orphaned children. At SUGAR, I have got the chance to interact with and add values to the lives of children at shelters. Leading a network of hundreds of volunteers and enlisting support from our 33,000 followers on Facebook, I’m contented that I can help take care of them both mentally and financially.
Regular trips to orphanages have brought home to me many heartful values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science at an aesthetic glance</title>
      <link>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/sci-glance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 20:38:21 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/sci-glance/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My four-year journey at a glance</title>
      <link>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/four-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 20:17:48 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/four-year/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A revitalizing piece</title>
      <link>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/revitalizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 20:11:32 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/revitalizing/</guid>
      <description>Whenever my triumphant steps pass a reflective surface, my course changes as every possible angle is now brutally reflected. I used to dread my plump silhouette.
From a young age, I was accustomed to being called chubby. My relatives would never stop reprimanding me for being overweight, and my classmates who were jealous of my academic achievements told me my size would prevent me from ever being successful.
These remarks only served to make me study harder to shift their attention from my appearance to my accomplishments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Proud Mom</title>
      <link>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/a-proud-mom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 14:02:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://btrhoang.github.io/blog/a-proud-mom/</guid>
      <description>I arrived home at 10 p.m. on the final day of the three-day conference. I didn’t cry, neither in the closing ceremony nor the dinner party, despite seeing many of my members failing to choke back their tears. Instead, I calmly slept for twelve hours to replenish my energy, getting myself ready for the upcoming post-event tasks.
As the Deputy Secretary General, I long attached myself to the responsibility of remaining mentally strong on all occasions so that my members can always have a firm shoulder to lean on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
